Howard Ship Yards and Dock Company mss., 1810-1967 LMC 2278
Lilly Library
Howard Ship Yards and Dock Company mss.
1810-1967
Lilly Library
LMC 2278
266739 Items
The Howard Ship Yards & Dock Company mss., 1834-1942, are papers of the company of that name of Jeffersonville, Indiana, builders of steamboats, barges, towboats, etc. The papers in the collection consist of account books and other financial records, letters received, letter-copybooks, blueprints, drawings, and some photographs.
Access Restrictions
Access to this collection requires advance notice. Please contact the curator for additional information.
Biographical Note
The Howard Ship Yard Company was founded by James Howard, who was born in Oldham, England, on September 1, 1814, and brought to Cincinnati, Ohio, by his parents in 1820. After serving an apprenticeship to William Hartshorn, steamboat builder of Cincinnati, Howard established his own yards at Jeffersonville, Indiana, in 1834. In 1836 he moved his yards to Madison, Indiana, were he remained until 1844. The depression of 1844 induced him to spend the years 1844-1845 as an engineer and ship carpenter on the Ohio and Mississippi rivers. In 1846 he returned to the construction of steamboats locating his yards at Shippingsport, Kentucky. Soon he moved to Louisville, and from there in 1849 back to Jeffersonville, which became his permanent location. At this time he took his brother Daniel Howard in the firm. In 1865 his younger brother, John C. Howard, and his son, Edmonds John Howard, became his partners under the firm name, James Howard and Company. After the drowning of James Howard in 1876, his son and brother continued the business until the retirement of John C. Howard in 1888 left Edmonds John Howard in control. Under his presidency the business was expanded to include shipyards and marine ways at Cincinnati, Ohio, Madison and Jeffersonville, Indiana, Mound City, Illinois, and Paducah, Kentucky. In January 1919 Clyde Howard and James E. Howard succeeded their father in the shipbuilding business. James was vice-president and buyer and Clyde the secretary and treasurer. The chair of president remained vacant. Upon the retirement of Clyde, James became the principal owner and president of the company.
From 1925 to 1941 when the United States government assumed control of the Howard Ship Yards and Dock Company, Mrs. Loretta M. Howard, (Mrs. James E. Howard), was secretary and treasurer of the firm.
The Navy planned the construction of a new type vessel at the Jeffersonville Boat and Machine Company yards and early in 1942 the War Department commenced condemnation proceedings.
This shipyard is said to be the oldest continuous, at one time the largest, and in the post Civil War period the most famous concern of its kind on Western rivers.
For the history of the firm, lists of boats constructed by it, and biographies of members of the Howard family see Lewis C. Baird's Baird's History of Clark County, Indiana. (Indianapolis, Ind., 1909), pp. 330-353, 431-433, 464-466, 733; Stephen G. Savage, "James Howard of Jeffersonville, Master Builder of Steamboats," master of arts thesis, Department of History, Indiana University, October 1952; and Charles Preston Fishbaugh, "The Howard Shipyards of Jeffersonville, Indiana, An Economic History," doctoral dissertation, School of Business, Indiana University, 1967, which was published as From Paddle Wheels to Propellers, Indianapolis. Indiana Historical Society, 1970 (VM301 .H6 F53).
The thesis and dissertation are filed with the collection.
Note on Indexing Term - "Art": Of interest are the many blueprints and drawings of boats in the collection.
Scope and Contents
The Howard Ship Yards & Dock Company mss. consists of correspondence, 1847-1955; financial records, 1810-1955, including account books, cashbooks, ledgers, time books, payrolls, branch journals, and accident record books; and legal files, 1913-1955. The collection also includes photographs and specifications of boats. Charles Fishbaugh's history of Howard Shipyards is also filed with the collection.
Arrangement
This collection consists of the following series: I. Correspondence, II. Business/Financial, III. Journals, IV. Legal, V. Minutes, VI. Miscellaneous, VII. Pictures, VIII. Plans, IX. Specifications, X. Writings, and XI. Printed.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1990
Related Materials
See the Howard Oral History mss. and Howard Boat Photograph mss., also at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Art; Voyages and travels; Boatbuilding; Boatyards; Indiana; Howard Ship Yards and Dock Company
- Correspondence
  - 1847-1874 June (Box 1)
  - 1874 July-1877 (Box 2)
  - 1878-1880 (Box 3)
  - 1881-1889 (Box 4)
  - 1890-1903 (Box 5)
  - 1903-1906 (Box 6)
  - 1907-1909 August (Box 7)
  - 1909 September-1911 May (Box 8)
  - 1911 June-1913 June (Box 9)
  - 1913 July-1915 May (Box 10)
  - 1915 June-1916 September (Box 11)
  - 1916 October-1918 (Box 12)
  - 1919 January-September (Box 13)
  - 1919 October-1920 March (Box 14)
  - 1920 April-October (Box 15)
  - 1920 November-1923 June (Box 16)
  - 1923 July-1924 May (Box 17)
  - 1924 June-1925 February (Box 18)
  - 1925 March-September (Box 19)
  - 1925 October-1926 April (Box 20)
  - 1926 May-November (Box 21)
  - 1926 December-1927 June (Box 22)
  - 1927 July-1928 March (Box 23)
  - 1928 April-November (Box 24)
  - 1928 December-1929 July (Box 25)
  - 1929 August-1930 March (Box 26)
  - 1930 April-October (Box 27)
  - 1930 November-1931 March (Box 28)
  - 1931 April-July (Box 29)
  - 1931 August-1932 January (Box 30)
  - 1932 February-June (Box 31)
  - 1932 July-1933 March (Box 32)
  - 1933 April-December (Box 33)
  - 1934 (Box 34)
  - 1935-1936 March (Box 35)
  - 1936 August-1937 July (Box 36)
  - 1937 August-1940 May (Box 37)
  - 1940 June-1955 (Box 38)
  - Undated
  - Nutop Company, Inc.
- Letters
  - 1874, November 19 - 1876, July 25 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1876, August 1 - 1878, November 12 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1878, November 15 - 1881, March 8 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1881, March 9 - 1884, April 10 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1884, April 12 - 1886, March 17 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1886, March 12 - 1889, March 16 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1889, March 16 - 1893, February 16 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1894, September 12 - 1896, May 5 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1896, May 5 - 1897, March 25 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1901, April 16 - 1904, December 15 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1903, August 20 - 1905, May 16 (Box 39, Box 40)
  - 1855, June 1 - 1862, April 28 (Bound 56)
- Balance Sheets
  - 1870, September - 1872, August
- Financial
  - 1847-1907 (Box 41)
  - 1908-1920 (Box 42)
  - 1921-1926 September (Box 43)
  - 1926 October-1929 (Box 44)
  - 1930-1940 (Box 45)
  - 1847-1940
  - Directors' Meeting, Howard Shipyards Co., 1903-1908
  - 1941-1951; undated (Box 46)
- Journal (Box 46)
- Legal Files
  - 1810-1912 (Box 46)
  - 1913-1929 (Box 47)
  - 1930-1955 (Box 48)
- Minutes
  - 1905-1941 (Box 48)
- Pictures
  - A-F (Box 77)
  - G-Z & miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous
- Plans
  - 6496-6697 (Box 49)
- Specifications
  - By Boat Name - A (Box 49)
  - By Boat Name - B-C (Box 50)
  - By Boat Name - D-H (Box 51)
  - By Boat Name - Hi-Kd (Box 52)
  - By Boat Name - Ke-O (Box 53)
  - By Boat Name - P-Th (Box 54)
  - By Boat Name - Ti-Z (Box 55)
  - By Company - A-Az (Box 55)
  - By Company - B-Cq (Box 56)
  - By Company - Cr-Hz (Box 57)
  - By Company - I-Mar (Box 58)
  - By Company - Mas-Roo (Box 59)
  - By Company - Rop-Tg (Box 60)
  - By Company - Th-U.S. Agencies (Box 61)
  - By Company - U.S. Agencies (Box 62, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66)
  - By Company - Up-Z (Box 67)
  - By Type of Craft - A-F (Box 67)
  - By Type of Craft - G-Z (Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous
  - Non-boat
  - Steel for Steamer Pilgrim
  - Sargent Floyd
- Writings (Box 69)
- Printed (Box 69)
- Payrolls
  - Box I, 1930-1932 (Box 69)
  - Box II, 1926 (Box 69)
  - Box III, 1927 (Box 70)
  - Box IV, Mound City, 1922-1923 (Box 70)
  - Box V, 1914-1918 (Box 70)
  - Box VI, Madison, 1931-1934 (Box 70)
  - Box VII, Mound City, 1918-1921 (Box 70)
  - Box VIII, Jeffersonville, 1931-1934 (Box 70)
  - Box IX, Jeffersonville (Box 71)
- Foreman's Records
  - 1932 (Box 71)
- Howard Family
  - Correspondence and documents, 1864-1946 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence and documents, 1946-1951 (Box 74)
  - Bills and receipts (Box 74)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 74)
  - Notebooks and diaries, 1857-1923 (Box 75)
  - Poetry and photographs (Box 76)
  - Printed material, 1869-1942 (Box 76)
- Time Sheets
  - Box I (Box 71)
  - Box II (Box 72)
  - Box III (Box 72)
  - Box IV (Box 72)
  - Box V (Box 72)
  - Box VI (Box 73)
  - Box VII (Box 73)
- Freight Reports
  - 1862, May 1 - 1863, August 1 (Folio 15)
  - 1867, January 1 - 1868, September 1 (Folio 15)
  - 1868, November 1 - 1870, August 1 (Folio 15)
- Newspapers and clippings, 1876-1952 (Box 76)
- Weekly Job Reports
  - Weekly pay roll at Jeffersonville, 1933, January 7 - October 15; 1937, July 23 - November 26; 1938, February 4 - December 30; 1939, January 6 - 1940, March 14 (Box 91)
  - Weekly pay roll at Madison, 1915, July 24 - December 31; 1916, January 7 - December 29; 1917, January 5 - July 20 (Box 91)
  - Weekly job reports - Cincinnati branch, 1914, July 10 - 1917, December 28 (Box 92)
  - Job reports on Inland Navigation Co. Barge No. 1, Madison branch, 1914, July 10 - 1915, July 23 (Box 92)
  - Job Reports on specific boats, 1914, April 24 - 1918, April 5 (Box 92)
  - Weekly job reports - Paducah branch, 1914, July 10 - 1918, December 27 (Box 93)
  - Weekly job reports - Mound City branch, 1914, July 10 - 1918, October 11 (Box 94)
- Bound Volumes
  - Accident record book, 1928-1936 (Bound 13)
  - HSY & DC Account book, 1887, May 15 - 1891, March 19 (Bound 136)
  - HSY & DC Account book, 1905, November 17 - 1914, May 22 (Bound 72)
  - HSY & DC Accounts payable, 1909, July - 1914, May (Bound 206)
  - HSY & DC Accounts receivable, 1903, June 1 - 1914, May 30 (Bound 207)
  - Mississippi Valley Marine Railway & Dock Co. Account payable index (Bound 208)
  - Paducah Marine Railway - Account book, 1904-1914 (Bound 248)
  - Paducah Marine Railway - Accounts payable index (Bound 209)
  - Auditor's report, 1904, January 1 - 1913, December 31 (Bound 210)
  - Auditor's report, 1904, January 1 - 1914, January 1 (Bound 211)
  - Howard, Edmund J. Bank book, 1891, April 1 - 1899, June 29 (Bound 31)
  - HSY & DC Bill copybook, 1886, April 2 - 1890, August 12 (Bound 104)
  - HSY & DC Bill copybook, 1903, June 17 - 1904, September 30 (Bound 103)
  - HSY & DC Bill copybook, 1904, September 13 - 1906, November 28 (Bound 102)
  - HSY & DC Bill copybook, 1906, November 5 - 1909, August 23 (Bound 58)
  - HSY & DC Bill copybook, 1910, May 13 - 1919, January 31 (Bound 60)
  - Record of boats built, 1883-1929 (Bound 18)
  - HSY & DC Boats built record, 1903, June 17 - 1915, November 23 (Bound 59)
  - Boats built record, 1925, November 11 - 1933, April 11 (Bound 52)
  - Record of boat drawings, 1926, October 1 - 1932, March 22 (Bound 50)
  - Boat estimates, 1885, January 20 - 1896, December (Bound 112)
  - Boat estimates, 1904, January 23 - 1906, November 13 (Bound 111)
  - Boat estimates, 1907, June 21 - "Late in" 1918 (Bound 22)
  - Boat estimates, 1915, October 23 - 1923, August 28 (Bound 70)
  - Howard, Clyde - Boat estimate record, 1918, November 13 - 1919, October 6 (Bound 17)
  - Boat estimates, 1936-1937 (Bound 32)
  - Baton Rouge Ferry estimate, undated (Bound 19)
  - Ohio Falls Street Railway Co. - Car Receipts, 1889, May 28 - 1892, August 31 (Bound 57)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1851, July 1 - 1853, February 7 (Bound 56)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1851, July 11 - 1852, July 3 (Bound 75)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1852, August 7 - 1853, April 20 (Bound 74)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1853, April 20 - December 31 (Bound 71)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1854, January 2 - 1855, May 12 (Bound 119)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1855, May 21 - 1856, May 31 (Bound 124)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1858, January 1 - 1863, March 5 (Bound 123)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1863, March 5 - 1866, November 7 (Bound 45)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1870, October 1 - 1875, October 1 (Bound 44)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1875, October 1 - 1884, May 10 (Bound 156)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1877, January 10 - 1882, December 2 (Bound 129)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1882, December 2 - 1885, September 28 (Bound 138)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1884, April 26 - 1890, August 30 (Bound 234)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1890, September 1 - 1895, April 30 (Bound 235)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1892, March 19 - 1904, March 7 (Bound 152)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1903, June 1 - 1913, February 28 (Bound 228)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1913, March 1 - 1914, July 17 (Bound 226)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1914, July 3 - 1918, October 1 (Bound 225)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1914, July 25 - 1918, September 1 (Bound 134)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1916, April 15 - 1917, November 21 (Bound 29)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1918, January 1 - June 15 (Bound 33)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1919, January 11 - 1925, September 5 (Bound 183)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1919, January 23 - 1920, December 13 (Bound 182)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1920, December 10 - 1923, March 24 (Bound 215)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1923, March 24 - 1925, February 28 (Bound 216)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1925, March 2 - August 31 (Bound 217)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1925, September 1 - 1932, November 30 (Bound 214)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1925, September 1 - 1932, December 23 (Bound 213)
  - HSY & DC Cashbooks, 1937, April 1 - December 30 (Bound 181)
  - Cincinnati branch - Cashbook, 1913, January 3 - 1918, February 16 (Bound 178)
  - Mound City branch - Cashbook, 1915, November 1 - 1925, February 25 (Bound 177)
  - Nutop Co., Inc. Cashbook, 1916, October 17 - 1917, May 8 (Bound 53)
  - Queen City Marine Railway Co. Cashbook, 1904, January 9 - 1912, December 31 (Bound 157)
  - HSY & DC Compensation Insurance, 1939, July 20 - 1941, May (Bound 212)
  - Construction record, 1925 (Bound 34)
  - Construction materials for boats, undated (Bound 251)
  - Construction record, undated
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1856, June 6 - 1858, September 2 (Bound 184)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1859, March 2 - 1866, March 26 (Bound 173)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1861, August 5 - 1865, March 31 (Bound 172)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1865, July 1 - 1868, December 2 (Bound 240)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1868, November 30 - 1870, October 31 (Bound 190)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1869, July 10 - 1871, February 22 (Bound 233)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1870, November 1 - 1872, November 5 (Bound 192)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1872, October 14 - 1874, June 11 (Bound 185)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1872, November 1 - 1875, January 29 (Bound 193)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1874, June 13 - 1875, November 26 (Bound 188)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1875, November 27 - 1877, August 11 (Bound 187)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1877, January 2 - 1880, December 24 (Bound 195)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1877, August 11 - 1879, February 3 (Bound 189)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1879, January 2 - 1881, February 11 (Bound 197)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1880, October 16 - 1884, July 28 (Bound 194)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1884, May 10 - 1894, December 31 (Bound 239)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1884, May 12 - 1887, April 1 (Bound 191)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1887, March 22 - 1889, March 23 (Bound 171)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1899, January 2 - 1903, January 19 (Bound 196)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1902, June 2 - 1903, September 2 (Bound 245)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1903, January 1 - 1904, November 26 (Bound 246)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1903, January 1 - 1905, June 10 (Bound 250)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1905, April 1 - 1907, March 23 (Bound 249)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1905, April 3 - 1907, October 30 (Bound 237)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1905, April 29 - 1911, April 6 (Bound 236)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1907, March 24 - 1909, June 29 (Bound 243)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1907, October 1 - 1911, April 7 (Bound 186)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1909, June 24 - 1912, November 15 (Bound 241)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1914, March 9 - 1917, May 29 (Bound 242)
  - HSY & DC Daybook, 1937, March 18 - 1940, November 12 (Bound 244)
  - Nutop Co., Inc. Daybook, 1918, May 18 - 1921, March 7 (Bound 55)
  - Straus Hotel - Daybook and Cash Account, 1881, November 2 - 1898, December 10 (Bound 54)
  - HSY & DC Diary, 1909, December 13 - 1925, February 24 (Bound 247)
  - HSY & DC Diary, 1911, July 12 - 1914, March 11 (Bound 68)
  - HSY & DC Diary, 1924, November 18 - 1925, February 19 (Bound 238)
  - HSY & DC Diary, undated (Bound 21)
  - Freightbook of the Steamer Highflyer, 1854, May 22 - 1855, December 26 (Bound 205)
  - Freightbook of the Steamer Highflyer, 1859, May 17 - 1860, January 27 (Bound 165)
  - Log - Diesel tug J. J. Hennen, 1930, October 10 - 1933, February 1 (Bound 14)
  - Inventory - Howard Ship Yards & Dock Co., 1928, December 31 (Bound 30)
  - Steel Inventory - Howard Ship Yards & Dock Co., 1929, October 25 (Bound 35)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1860, March 1 - 1866, December 1 (Bound 153)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1865, July 1 - 1874, December 31 (Bound 121)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1877, January 10 - 1886, June 1 (Bound 120)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1904, January 1 - 1913, October 1 (Bound 155)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1904, January 31 - 1918, December 31 (Bound 151)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1914, April 24 - 1918, February 14 (Bound 107)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1914, June - 1918, June 30 (Bound 162)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1914, July 6 - 1918, December 31 (Bound 154)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1917, September 1 - 1925, August 29 (Bound 163)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1918, January 1 - 1919, January 1 (Bound 149)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1919, April 19 - 1920, October 21 (Bound 164)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1919, June 30 - 1922, November 30 (Bound 150)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1920, October 1 - 1922, September 30 (Bound 159)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1922, October 1 - 1924, August 31 (Bound 158)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1922, December 5 - 1925, August 31 (Bound 148)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1924, September 1 - 1925, August 31 (Bound 160)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1925, September 1 - 1930, December 30 (Bound 174)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1925, September 1 - 1931, December 31 (Bound 139)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1926, January 1 - 1930, December 31 (Bound 142)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1928, October 1 - 1929, September 30 (Bound 125)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1936, February 7 - March 19 (Bound 20)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1936, August 28 - 1937, November 10 (Bound 73)
  - HSY & DC Journal, 1937, April 1 - 1939, December 30 (Bound 175)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Company Journal, 1903, June 1 - 1914, July 6 (Bound 82)
  - HSY & DC Cincinnati Branch Journal, 1904, January 1 - 1912, December 31 (Bound 166)
  - HSY & DC Cincinnati Branch Journal, 1913, January 4 - 1918, February 19 (Bound 170)
  - HSY & DC Madison Branch Journal, 1925, September 5 - 1929, December 31 (Bound 176)
  - HSY & DC Mound City Branch Journal, 1904, January 1 - 1915, October 31 (Bound 144)
  - HSY & DC Mound City Branch Journal, 1915, November 5 - 1925, March 31 (Bound 143)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Journal, 1904, January 1 - 1913, December 31 (Bound 161)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Journal, 1904, January 2 - 1920, November 18 (Bound 204)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Journal, 1914, January 2 - 1920, December 31 (Bound 147)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Journal, 1919, January 1 - 1920, October 5 (Bound 146)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1839, March 30 - 1851, July 12 (Bound 67)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1850, March 30 - 1868, October 6 (Bound 40)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1851, July 1 - 1854, December 30 (Bound 145)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1851, July 12 - 1853, February 5 (Bound 39)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1855, January 1 - 1859, February 26 (Bound 97)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1859, February 1 - 1872, June 8 (Bound 108)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1860, March 1 - 1866, December 1 (Bound 89)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1865, July 1 - 1874, December 31 (Bound 101)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1872, February 3 - 1880, June 30 (Bound 110)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1877, January 13 - 1883, December 19 (Bound 84)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1877, February 26 - 1884, July 4 (Bound 109)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1884, April 30 - 1898, January 1 (Bound 100)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1884, May 13 - 1896, January 18 (Bound 87)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1893, December 14 - 1908, July 20 (Bound 86)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1903, July 31 - 1917, December 31 (Bound 83)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1903, December 31 - 1913, October 1 (Bound 88)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1904-1913 (Bound 99)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1914, July 6 - 1919, January 1 (Bound 38)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1915-1918 (Bound 98)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1918, January 1 - 1923, January 1 (Bound 85)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1918, January 1 - 1924, March 13 (Bound 42)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1919, November 26 - 1925, March 31 (Bound 43)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1923, January 1 - 1925, March 31 (Bound 61)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1925, April 1 - 1927, December 31 (Bound 63)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1925, April 1 - 1929, April 11 (Bound 41)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1925, August 10 - 1937, July 31 (Bound 64)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1928 (Bound 65)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1929, January 1 - 1930, December 31 (Bound 66)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1931 (Bound 62)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1936, January 1 - 1937, March 31 (Bound 78)
  - HSY & DC Ledger, 1936, December 10 - 1941, June 28 (Bound 69)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Co. Ledger, 1903, May 7 - 1913, December (Bound 221)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Co. Ledger, 1903, June 1 - 1914, June 12 (Bound 230)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Co. Ledger, 1903, June 1 - 1914, July 6 (Bound 222)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Co. Ledger Index (2 volumes), undated (Bound 223, Bound 224)
  - Arc Flame Manufacturing Co. Ledger, 1918, June 30 - 1919, January 1 (Bound 27)
  - HSY & DC Cincinnati Branch Ledger, 1913, January 1 - 1918, January 31 (Bound 219)
  - HSY & DC Madison Branch Ledger, 1925, June 1 - 1931, December 31 (Bound 80)
  - HSY & DC Mound City Branch Ledger, 1904, January 16 - 1918, January 25 (Bound 15, Bound 220)
  - HSY & DC Mound City Branch Ledger, 1918, February 7 - 1923, January 1 (Bound 198)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Ledger, 1904, January 16 - 1918, January 25 (Bound 231)
  - HSY & DC Paducah Branch Ledger, 1918, January 1 - 1920, December 30 (Bound 218)
  - Paducah Marine Railway Company - Ledger Index (Bound 179)
  - Mississippi Valley Marine Railway & Dock Co. Ledger, 1883, September 1 - 1903, August 10 (Bound 180)
  - Queen City Marine Railway Co. Ledger, 1904, January 1 - 1913, January 1 (Bound 227)
  - Memorandum book, 1930, May 20 - 1938, September (Bound 137)
  - HSY & DC Notes Payable & Receivable, 1865, September 16 - 1879, October 31 (Bound 76)
  - HSY & DC Notes Payable & Receivable, 1887, January 29 - 1897, June 28 (Bound 81)
  - HSY & DC Notes Payable & Receivable, 1903, May 7 - 1914, June 11 (Bound 229)
  - HSY & DC Notes Payable & Receivable, 1904, May 12 - 1918, November 15
  - HSY & DC Notes Payable & Receivable, 1930, February 5 - 1932, June 4 (Bound 77)
  - HSY & DC Planning Mill Book, 1884, May 15 - 1891, November 17 (Bound 79)
  - HSY & DC Stock certificate book, 1904, January 16 - November 5 (Bound 47)
  - HSY & DC Stock certificate book, 1912, September 3 (Bound 46)
  - HSY & DC Stock certificate book, 1912, August 27 - 1917, December 3 (Bound 49)
  - HSY & DC Stock certificate book, 1917, December 4 - 1936, March 9 (Bound 23)
  - HSY & DC Stock certificate book, 1927, July 19 - 1941, January 17 (Bound 25)
  - American Rivers Shipbuilding Co. Stock certificate book (2 volumes), 1903, June 1 (Bound 24, Bound 26)
  - Mississippi Valley Marine Railway and Dock Co. Stock certificate book, 1883, September 1 - 1904, December 1 (Bound 48)
  - HSY & DC Stock ledger, 1912, August 12 - 1918, July 15 (Bound 36)